A Finding Aid to the Lilian Swann Saarinen Papers, circa 1909-1977, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
Lilian Swann Saarinen papers
circa 1909-1977
Archives of American Art
Saarinen, Lilian Swann, 1912-1995
AAA.saarlili
Archival Resource Key
9 Linear feet
The papers of Cambridge sculptor and illustrator, Lilian Swann Saarinen, measure nine linear feet and date from circa 1909 to 1977. The collection documents Saarinen's career through correspondence with artists, architects, publishers, and gallery owners; writings and notes, including manuscripts and illustrations for children's books and publications; project and teaching files; financial records; artwork, including numerous project sketches; and photos of Saarinen and her artwork. Saarinen's personal life is also documented through diaries and correspondence with friends and family members, including Eero Saarinen, to whom she was married from 1939-1953.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged as 11 series.
Missing Title
Series 1: Biographical Material, circa 1930s-1960s (3 folders; Box 1, OV 12)
Series 2: Correspondence, 1920-1974 (1.9 linear feet; Boxes 1-2, 8, OV 12)
Series 3: Writings and Notes, 1920s-1973 (1.3 linear feet, Boxes 2-3, 8, OVs 13-16)
Series 4: Diaries, 1930-1973 (1.4 linear feet, Boxes 3-5, 8)
Series 5: Project Files, 1931-1966 (1.7 linear feet, Boxes 5-6, 8, OVs 17-19)
Series 6: Teaching Files, 1966-1970 (3 folders, Box 6)
Series 7: Financial Records, 1940s-1970s (2 folders, Box 6)
Series 8: Printed Material, circa 1930s-1970s (0.2 linear feet, Box 6)
Series 9: Scrapbooks, circa 1909-1974 (2 folders; Boxes 6, 9)
Series 10: Artwork, circa 1920s-circa 1960s (1.7 linear feet, Boxes 6-7, 9-10, OVs 20-27)
Series 11: Photographs, circa 1940s, 1977 (0.5 linear feet, Boxes 7, 11, OV 27)
Conditions Governing Access
Use of original papers requires an appointment and is limited to the Archives' Washington, D.C. Research Center. Contact Reference Services for more information.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Lilian Swann Saarinen donated the collection in 1975. She lent additional materials for microfilming in 1976.
Separated Materials
The Archives of American Art also holds material lent for microfilming (reels 1152 and 1192) including a scrapbook containing clippings, copies of letters and telegrams received, and reproductions of Saarinen's work. There is a copy of Saarinen's book, "Who Am I?", and three albums containing photographs of Saarinen, photographs and reproductions of her work, a list of exhibitions, quotes about her, and writings by her about sculpture. Lent material was returned to the lender and is not described in the collection container inventory.
Scope and Contents
The papers of Cambridge sculptor and illustrator, Lilian Swann Saarinen, measure nine linear feet and date from circa 1909 to 1977. The collection documents Saarinen's career through correspondence with artists, architects, publishers, and gallery owners; writings and notes, including manuscripts and illustrations for children's books and publications; project and teaching files; financial records; artwork, including numerous project sketches; and photos of Saarinen and her artwork. Saarinen's personal life is also documented through diaries and correspondence with friends and family members, including Eero Saarinen, to whom she was married from 1939-1953.
Biographical material consists of resumes and biographical sketches, as well as a 1951 blueprint for the Eero Saarinen and Associates Office Building in Bloomfield Hills, Michigan.
Correspondence documents Saarinen's personal and professional life through letters to and from Eero Saarinen and other family members, including six letters from Loja Saarinen; correspondence with artists and architects, including Merle Armitage, Charles and Ray Eames, Carl Koch, Henry Kreis, Carl Milles, Laszlo and Sibyl Moholy-Nagy, Robert Venturi, and Harry Weese; and friends and colleagues at the Cranbrook Academy of Art and Knoll Associates. Also documented is Saarinen's business relationship with Midtown Galleries and Caresse Crosby, and publishers and publications including Child Life, Interiors, Otava Publishing Company, and Reynal & Hitchcock, Inc.
Writings and Notes document Saarinen's work on several children's publications, including Picture Book Zoo (1935) and Who Am I? (1946), through correspondence, notes, manuscript drafts, and extensive sketches. This series also includes Saarinen's ideas for other publications and incorporates some early writings and notes, as well as typescripts of her reminiscences about Eliel Saarinen, the Saarinen family, and the Cranbrook Academy of Art.
Diaries consist of bound diary volumes, loose-leaf journal entries, and heavily annotated engagement calendars, documenting Saarinen's personal life, artistic aspirations, and career development from the 1930s-1970s. This material provides a deeply personal view of the emotional landscape of Saarinen's life, her struggles to balance her identity as a working artist with the roles of wife, mother, and homemaker, and the complex, and often competing, relationships within the renowned architectural family into which she married.
Project files document Saarinen's work on book cover designs, federal and post office commissions in Bloomfield, Indiana, Carlisle, Kentucky, and Evanston, Illinois, reliefs for the Crow Island School in Winnetka, Illinois, and other important commissions including the Harbor National Bank Clock in Boston, Massachusetts, the KLM Airlines installation at JFK Airport, the Fountain of Noah sculpture at the Northland Center in Detroit, Michigan, and the interior of Toffenetti's restaurant in Chicago, Illinois. Also documented is her role in designs for the Gateway Arch in St. Louis, with Eero Saarinen.
Teaching files document Saarinen's "Language of Clay Course" which she taught at Cambridge Art Center and the Massachusetts Institute of Technology.
Financial records document exhibition and sales expenses for two exhibitions, including her show at G Place Gallery in 1944.
Printed material consists of clippings about Saarinen and her family, exhibition announcements and catalogs for herself and others, and reference files from the 1930s-1940s, primarily comprising clippings of animals.
Additional printed material documenting Saarinen's career can be found in one of two scrapbooks found in the collection. An additional scrapbook consists of clippings relating primarily to Saarinen's parents.
Artwork comprises extensive sketches, particularly animal and figure sketches, in graphite, crayon, ink, pastel, and watercolor. The sketches demonstrate in particular Saarinen's developing interest in and skill with animal portraiture from her childhood to the 1960s.
Photographs are primarily of artwork and Saarinen's 1944 exhibition at G Place Gallery. Also found are one negative of Saarinen, probably with Eero Saarinen, and a group photo including Lilian, Eero, and Eliel Saarinen with the model for the Detroit Civic Center, circa 1940s.
Biographical / Historical
Cambridge artist and sculptor, Lilian Swann Saarinen (1912-1995), studied at the Art Students League with Alexander Archipenko in 1928, and later with Albert Stewart and Heninz Warneke from 1934-1936, before moving to Michigan where she studied with Carl Milles at the Cranbrook Academy of Art from 1936-1940. Saarinen was an accomplished skier and a member of the 1936 US Olympic ski team.
At Cranbrook, Swann met architect Eero Saarinen, whom she married in 1939. She subsequently worked with Saarinen's design group on a variety of projects, including the Westward Expansion Memorial, which later became known as the "Gateway Arch" in St. Louis. Lilian and Eero had a son, Eric, and a daughter, Susie, before divorcing in 1953.
Saarinen, who had developed an affinity for drawing animals in childhood, specialized in animal portraits in a variety of sculptural media. In 1939, she exhibited her sculpture Night, which depicted Bagheera the panther from Rudyard Kipling's Jungle Book, at the World's Fair. The sculpture was placed in the Boston Public Garden in 1986. In the 1930s and 1940s Saarinen was commissioned to work on a variety of architectural projects, including reliefs for post offices in Bloomfield, Indiana, Carlisle, Kentucky, and Evanston, Illinois, and the Crow Island School in Winnetka, Illinois. She also executed commissions for the Harbor National Bank in Boston, KLM (Royal Dutch Airlines) at JFK Airport, the Northland shopping Center in Detroit Michigan, and Toffenetti's Restaurant in Chicago.
Saarinen was a contributing author and illustrator for a variety of publications, including Child Life, Interiors and Portfolio: An Intercontinental Quarterly. In 1935 she illustrated Picture Book Zoo for the Bronx Zoo and in 1946 Reynal & Hitchcock, Inc. published Who Am I?, a children's book which Saarinen wrote and illustrated.
Saarinen taught ceramic sculpture to soldiers for the Red Cross Arts and Skills Unit rehabilitation program in 1945, served on the Visiting Committee to the Museum School at the Museum of Fine Arts, Boston, from 1959-1964, where she taught ceramics, and later taught a course entitled "The Language of Clay" at the Cambridge Art Center and the Massachusetts Institute of Technology. One of Saarinen's private students at Cambridge was her cousin, Edie Sedgwick.
Saarinen died in Cohasset, Massachusetts, in 1995 at the age of 83.
Existence and Location of Copies
The bulk of the collection was digitized in 2017 with funding provided by The Walton Family Foundation. Material not digitized includes blank pages of diaries, unannotated pages of engagement calendars, routine financial transactions, blank versos of photographs, and duplicates.
Material lent for microfilming is available on 35mm microfilm reels 1152 and 1192 at the Archives of American Art offices and through interlibrary loan.
Sculptors -- Massachusetts -- Cambridge; Women artists; Art -- Study and teaching; Illustrated books, Children's; Gateway Arch (Saint Louis, Mo.); Blueprints; Sculpture, Modern -- 20th century -- United States; Diaries; Illustrations; Illustrators -- Massachusetts; Sketches; Art commissions; Art, Municipal; Photographs; Scrapbooks; Women sculptors; Women illustrators; Midtown Galleries (New York, N.Y.); Reynal & Hitchcock; Venturi, Robert; Saarinen, Loja; G Place Gallery (Washington, D.C.); Knoll Associates, inc.; Massachusetts Institute of Technology -- Faculty; Kreis, Henry, 1899-1963; Milles, Carl, 1875-1955; Cambridge Art Center; Eames, Charles; Eames, Ray; Saarinen, Eero, 1910-1961; Saarinen, Eliel, 1873-1950; Moholy-Nagy, László, 1895-1946; Moholy-Nagy, Sibyl, 1905-; Otava Publishing Company; Koch, Carl; Armitage, Merle, 1893-1975; Crosby, Caresse, 1892-; Cranbrook Academy of Art -- Faculty; Weese, Harry, 1915-1998
- Biographical Material, circa 1930s-1960s; Series 1; Archival Resource Key; 3 Folders Box 1, OV 12
  Scope and Contents
  Biographical material consists of résumés and biographical sketches written by Saarinen, and a 1951 blueprint of the Eero Saarinen and Associates office building in Bloomfield Hills, Michigan, labeled "July/54 Kiln data."
  Existence and Location of Copies
  Series is scanned in entirety.
  - Blueprint, Eero Saarinen and Associates Office Building, 1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Oversized material housed in OV 12
  - Resumes and Biographical Notes, circa 1930s-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Oversized Blueprint, Eero Saarinen and Associates Office Building scanned with Box 1, Folder 1, Archival Resource Key (Box OV 12)
- Correspondence, 1920-1974; Series 2; Archival Resource Key; 1.9 Linear feet Boxes 1-2, 8, OV 12
  Arrangement
  Correspondence is arranged alphabetically. Correspondents who are represented by four or more items are housed in named files; all others are housed in general files for the corresponding letter of the alphabet.
  Saarinen's correspondence files document her personal life and career. Incoming letters form the bulk of the series, but are interspersed with outgoing letters, often in the form of drafts handwritten by Saarinen. Personal correspondence includes letters written between Lilian and Eero Saarinen, which provide insight into their relationship during the 1940s and early 1950s, and their decision to divorce in 1953. These letters also reference professional projects, including Eero Saarinen's involvement in the design of the Antioch College residence halls. Other letters describe Saarinen's planning meetings for the UNESCO headquarters in Paris, and enclose sketches of his preliminary ideas for the project.
  Many letters from Susan Hammond, Saarinen's mother, chronicle events in the Swann and Sedgwick families. Hammond frequently enclosed letters sent to her by others about Saarinen in her letters to Saarinen. Family correspondence includes letters from Saarinen's son, Eric, her sister Lucy Livingston Schwartz, letters from other members of the Swann family, and a letter from her cousin, Edie Sedgwick.
  Letters which document Saarinen's professional life include correspondence with publishers and publications such as Child Life, for which Saarinen provided illustrations; Interiors regarding the publication of an article by Saarinen about her and her work; Otava Publishing Company, including the 1956 contract for the Finnish edition of Who Am I?; Reynal & Hitchcock, Inc., relating to the original publication of Who Am I? in 1946; and Rutgers University Press regarding Saarinen's proposed jacket design for the cover of A Short Chronology of American History 1492-1950 (1952) by Irving S. and Nell M. Kull. Additional correspondence relating to Saarinen's writings can be found in Series 3: Writings and Notes.
  Also found is correspondence with Caresse Crosby regarding the consignment of Saarinen's artwork to Gump's and other galleries in the 1940s, and referencing Crosby's Portfolio: An Intercontinental Quarterly, for which Saarinen provided illustrations. Correspondence with Alan D. Gruskin of Midtown Galleries, who Saarinen contracted to represent her nationally from 1943-1948, includes Saarinen's sketches for her 1944 exhibition at G Place Gallery in Washington D. C., under the direction of Caresse Crosby.
  The series includes substantial correspondence with other artists and architects, many of whom were personal friends of Saarinen, including Merle Armitage, Walter Baermann, Alexander Calder, Charles and Ray Eames, Carl Koch, Henry Kreis, Carl Milles, Laszlo and Sibyl Moholy-Nagy, Robert Venturi, and Harry Weese. Also found is correspondence with the design firm Knoll Associates, Cranbrook Academy of Art directors and artists Soltan Sepeshy, Maija Grotell and Marianne Strengell, six letters from Loja Saarinen, and a telegram from Eliel Saarinen.
  The bulk of the correspondence relating to Saarinen's sculpture commissions can be found in Series 5: Project Files, but related correspondence is scattered throughout this series.
  - Abernathy, J.T., 1956-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Arkell, John, 1938-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Armitage, Merle and Elsa, 1942-1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - A, General, 1937-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Baldinger, Wallace S., 1948-1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Bank of New York, 1946-1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Barns, Katrina McCormick, circa 1940s; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - B, General, 1937-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Calder, Alexander, 1940-1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Cavin, W. Brooks Jr., 1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Child Life, 1946-1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Congratulations/Thank You Letters for Picture Book Zoo, 1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Cranbrook Academy of Art (Maija Grotell, Zoltan Sepeshy, Marianne Strengell), 1940s-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Crosby, Caresse (Crosby Gallery of Modern Art), 1934-1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - C, General, 1939-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Danforth, Maija C., circa 1943-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - D, General, 1939-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Eames, Charles and Ray, 1970; circa 1947-1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Includes illustrated letters; oversized material housed in Box 8, Folder 1
  - English, Miller & Hockett, 1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - E, General, 1943-1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Falch, Hedi, 1940-1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - F, General, 1936-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Grandin, Isabella (Bella), 1960s-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - G, General, circa 1940-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Hallowell, Johnny and Sis, 1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Hammond, Susan and Paul, circa 1920s-circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Hammond, Susan and Paul, circa 1940-circa 1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Hammond, Susan and Paul, circa 1942-circa 1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Hammond, Susan and Paul, 1920-1927; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Hammond, Susan and Paul, 1928; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Hammond, Susan and Paul, 1929; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 33)
    Oversized material housed in Box 8, Folder 1
  - Hammond, Susan and Paul, 1930-1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Hammond, Susan and Paul, 1940-1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Hammond, Susan and Paul, 1946-1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Hammond, Susan and Paul, 1952-1953 July; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Hammond, Susan and Paul, 1953 August-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Hammond, Susan and Paul, 1970-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 39)
    One letter to Saarinen from 1974 encloses two photos of Lilian Swann Saarinen, circa 1935, and one photo of one of Saarinen's sculpture
  - Haskell, Helen, 1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - H, General, 1931-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Interiors, 1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - I, General, 1942-1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - J, General, 1944-1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Kiaer, Herman S, 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Kline, Robert and Norma, 1953-1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Knoll Associates, 1948-1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Koch, Carl, 1942-1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Kreis, Henry, 1940-1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - K, General, circa 1934-circa 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Lambie, Roxane, circa 1940s-1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Lambie, Roxane, circa 1940s-circa 1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Lambie, Roxane, circa 1940s-circa 1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Lambie, Roxane, circa 1940s-1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Lambie, Roxane, 1953-1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Lambie, Roxane, 1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Lambie, Roxane, 1955-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Lander, E. W., 1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Laughlin, James (Jay), circa 1939-1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Loth, David, 1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Lueders, J. E., circa 1940-1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Lütgerath, Hadwiga, 1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - L, General, 1939-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Includes letter from Anne Morrow Lindbergh
  - Midtown Galleries, circa 1941-1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 10)
    Oversized material housed in OV 12; includes sketches of exhibition layout
  - Milles, Carl, circa 1943-1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Moholy-Nagy, Laszlo and Sibyl, 1945-1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Moloney, James Clark, 1966-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Museum of Fine Arts, Boston, 1959-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Museum of Modern Art, 1943-1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - M, General, 1943-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Norton, Marthia, 1938-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - N, General, 1937-1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Otava Publishing Company, 1955-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - O, General, 1951-1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Perkins, Lawrence and Midge, 1940-1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Putnam, Brenda, 1934-1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - P, General, 1936-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Rathbone, Beatrice (Babs), circa 1940-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Reynal & Hitchcock, Inc., 1945-1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Roach, Ellie (Ellie Worthyn), circa 1940s-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Robinson, Maude, 1948-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Root, Clark, Buckner & Ballantine, 1945-1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Rutgers University Press, 1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - R, General, 1939-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Saarinen, Eero, circa 1940s-1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Saarinen, Eero, circa 1939-circa 1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Saarinen, Eero, 1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Saarinen, Eero, 1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Saarinen, Eero, 1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Saarinen, Loja, circa 1943-circa 1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Saunders, Louise and Silvia, circa 1940-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Schwartz, Lucy Livingston, 1940s-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 38)
    Includes photo of Swann Saarinen, circa June 1970
  - Stewart, Albert and Margaret, 1933-circa 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Syracuse Museum of Fine Arts, 1940-1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - S, General: S.-Sec, 1940-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - S, General: Sed-Sw, 1938-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - S, Illegible, 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Thank You Letters from Children for Who Am I?, 1946-1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - T, General, 1938-1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - United States Post Office, 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Venturi, Robert, 1953-1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - V, General, circa 1940s; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 48)
    Includes one black and white and one color photo of a sculpture by Swann Saarinen
  - Weese, Harry, circa 1940-1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Weese, Harry, 1945-1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Weese, Harry E., 1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Winnetka Public Schools, 1945-1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - W, General, circa 1940, 1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Y-Z, General, 1942, 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - First Names Only, Archival Resource Key (Box 2)
    - Alice, Anna-Greta, 1940s-1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 55)